TSMC popped on earnings, but that's
because their earnings were very good.
>> TSMC earning report saw 25% jump in
profit on the AI boom. It seems like the
market
>> Right in a bubble, you just say we love
it. It doesn't matter if it's got
anything to do with it. Let's pile in.
That's not to say that there won't be
losers. This is a disruptive technology.
Companies that have operated in
industries for quite a while, if they
have not adjusted, they are at risk.
>> We've seen our parents. Let's not copy
them.
>> I'm a little biased because I love TSMC
and I'm a long-term holder.
>> these are winner-takes-most
opportunities,
some investors laugh when they hear
this, but obviously Elon Musk is putting
forward long-term plans
for data centers in space powered by
solar.
The technology builds new industries,
new services, new forms of
entertainment. The new not working is
going to mean something different than
what not working today.
I look at all of those macro things and
I think to myself, that is a call option
for disruptive innovation in 2026.
You're seeing the growing pains of
Bitcoin become an instrument, a part of
the overall global financial system.
That means
>> AI, crypto, macro, it can be very
overwhelming. What are three main trends
that you are paying attention to?
I am joined by Tom from Arc Invest. I'm
super excited to talk to him because I
read your report every single year. He's
the president and COO of Arc Invest.
Hello, Tom.
>> Hi. Thanks for having me.
>> Can we start with TSMC cuz I'm from
Taiwan?
>> Yeah.
>> Um TSMC earning report saw 25% jump in
profit on the AI boom in January and it
seems like the market is super
optimistic. However, we saw people, you
know, were a little nervous about the
drawdown.
>> Yeah.
>> How do we interpret it?
>> I I think this is a healthy part of
an industry that actually investors
should feel confident about, that it
actually has credibility. You know, when
something goes straight up and there's
not really a reality check, that's
actually a very unhealthy sign.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, what it means is that this
market is discerning, that it is
starting to
uh ask hard questions, that is looking
for relative winners and losers,
and it's asking questions about
valuations and whether they're
justified. I think it's not just um
TSMC, but it's also, you know, we we saw
news come out relative to people started
asking questions about Oracle, whether
there was double counting in their
revenue. We saw questions in parts of
the industry after Anthropic announced
some releases
um as to
uh Wall Street and global financial
markets asking who could be disrupted
that we haven't thought about. You know,
these are healthy questions. This is not
the type of question and environment
that you have in a bubble.
Right? In a bubble, you just say, "We
love it. It doesn't matter if it's got
anything to do with it. Let's pile in."
You know, you mentioned that TSMC popped
on their earnings, but that's because
their earnings were very good.
>> Yeah.
>> Right? That wasn't because they said AI,
that's because they demonstrated
real tangible results better than what
the market expected. And then there's
been volatility and pullback as the
space has had questions
in terms of other parts of that
ecosystem. So,
I think, to be honest, if I were what's
my main takeaway from that? My main
takeaway from that is that the market is
actually doing its job, that this is
that they've learned lessons from the
dot-com where they didn't ask any
questions, where earnings results were
popped on
metrics that were completely made up,
things like eye pricing eyeballs or user
growth, I mean things that are not
financial metrics, and stocks would go
up because of what they said on earnings
that just by being in the space. And I I
do feel like investors should have some
degree of confidence. Now, that's not to
say
that there won't be losers, right? This
is a disruptive technology.
There are parts of the market that are
going to be naturally displaced. There's
a creative destruction Schumpeterian
cycle going on here where companies that
have have operated in industries for
quite a while, if they have not
adjusted, they are at risk. I think
salesforce.com, you look at that stock,
and certainly they're trying to get into
the AI space, but there are a lot of
concerns that AI is already ahead. So,
you know, from an asset management
standpoint, it's our job to ensure that
we are in the beneficiaries, the
enablers, and the leaders, not in spaces
that are going to be disrupted or
vulnerable. Obviously, we have to pay
attention to to valuations as well, but
but the leaders are demonstrating strong
results. We also think that the adoption
rates, the penetration rates still have
a long way to go. They're rapid, they're
much faster than what the internet was,
but we're also we're we're back where
maybe 1995 was from internet adoption,
not 1999.
>> How do you know that?
>> Well, we're looking at the penetration
rates both from the user standpoint as
well as enterprise. And and when you
look at some of these numbers,
what's nice about it is it's pretty easy
to define the benefits that companies
can have from their monthly
subscriptions to something like ChatGPT.
And we keep track of
the ability of AI to perform a task that
takes a human roughly 30 minutes on
average. And how well can it do that?
When you start to look at the success
rate and the lack of error rate and
things you can apply that to, and you
cost out what that is. You can almost
pay for your company can pay almost pay
for a seat for of open AI in in about
one day's work.
>> You know, I'm a little biased because I
love TSMC and I'm a long-term holder.
So, I'm not too worried about TSMC, but
you know, there are companies that are
doubling their spending.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> Certainly.
>> You know, last year when there news
about this, people are like, "Oh, great.
You know, you guys are investing more."
But now people are worried about it.
>> Well, I mean, but this is a natural
technology cycle in that
some of the spending is pulled forward.
>> Mhm.
>> And it's companies who know that they
need to invest. They know they need to
embrace new technologies.
Um but sometimes that gets from a
company's standpoint, sometimes that
gets ahead of itself. In that the
company's not ready itself to
incorporate and to adopt and to
implement some of the technology.
Um
You know, and then you see some noise in
the data relative to that span, relative
to the integration.
I think, you know, again, this is pretty
natural in terms of technology adoption.
This is something that we've seen this
before a number of times.
Sometimes the market, when it's so
worried about certain valuations, you
know, takes that first pullback as
that the story was was false or that it
was overblown or that valuations were
wrong. When in reality is it's a natural
chasm from the early adoption. If you
think about an adoption curve, early
adopters race out, number of growth
rates look really impressive, but
they're off of very low bases.
The early adopters either they make
their spend and now they need to digest
it, implement it, use it. Or you have
excited exuberance that gets a little
ahead of itself. It drops off a little
while they strategically start to now
implement. If the market misinterprets
that as the story is over,
uh it can miss what what the real market
explo- opportunity is, which is
mainstream adoption of the car.
Mainstream being
depending on what site segment you're
talking about. Sometimes that's retail,
sometimes that's enterprise, sometimes
that's government defense.
Just depends which one we're talk which
company and what specialty.
I I think when you look at these curves
and you just take a step back, these are
impressive adoption curves. These are
real revenue growth, right? And so you
talked about spending a lot of money.
Yes, they are spending a lot of money.
That's true.
But they're also they've had no trouble
raising that capital. We're not in a
liquidity a tight liquidity situation.
And again, unlike the internet, there is
real revenue
to show for it. You know, if you look at
Open AI, Open AI generated the same
amount of annualized run rate revenue in
3 years that it took Google eight.
This is real explosive revenue growth
which to us signifies real companies
meeting real needs with real
opportunities. Now, they have to
execute, right? When you're burning that
much cash, you do have to execute. You
have to continue to improve to you have
to clearly articulate your market
segment. We think these are winner takes
most opportunities, but sometimes that's
misinterpreted
as saying, well, there'll be one LM and
not the others. You what you can have is
a bifurcation of market segments. Open
AI can go for the more retail segment
and you can have an Anthropic go more
enterprise. You know, that doesn't mean
it's when you say winner takes most, it
doesn't mean you have to choose between
those, but you need to understand that
within enterprise and within retail,
there might be a winner takes most
within those, though they can both win.
And honestly, you see that in in the
business model
when they articulate their business
model. Anthropic's projecting to turn to
profitability much faster than Open AI.
Open AI Sam Altman came out and pretty
clearly said, we're going to lose more
cash before we radically turn it on and
make profit
aggressively, but that makes sense for a
retail-focused company.
And, you know, there is to some degree,
remember we wasn't it was a very common
thing to hear to say Amazon will never
make money. They can't make money.
They'll never make money. And Facebook
doesn't make any revenue. It doesn't
make any money. It can never make any
money.
And you had um
Google even was not going to make money
until it made a lot of money. So,
I I'm not saying these are perfect
examples. I'm saying the market's heard
this before. Those the the companies I
had just said all have to certain
varying degrees a very retail-focused
aspect to them. It's critical that
OpenAI continue to develop to develop
its applications, establish itself if it
wants to be that winner takes most in
retail. They're certainly well
positioned. It doesn't mean that the
others can't look at enterprise and look
at government and defense and other
aspects as well and be leaders as well
and they should invest accordingly and
their business model should fit that
segment you know, that might look
different. And again, that's healthy for
the market. We don't want these all to
look the same. If they all look the
same, there's probably something wrong
because these segments are very
different. Um but
look, I think the market's asking hard
questions right now, but investors
should feel confident by the market
asking hard questions. It's when the
market doesn't ask hard questions that
they should be worried even when things
are going up.
>> We're talking about AI a lot. Is the
main constraint energy?
>> I think energy and water I mean, natural
resources, water is required for cooling
data centers.
Um
obviously, energy is required to power
these data centers. Now, if you look,
for example, at the energy output
increase annualized year-over-year,
I mean, China alone basically grows its
energy output at a rate that can't
account for what we see data center
proliferation. So, some of these
short-term
energy fears, we think are overblown.
Also, this is a similar story to a
number of things. As the technology gets
better, the infrastructure and the
ecosystem becomes more efficient. Energy
efficiency,
you know, very much being one of them.
But, there are hard questions relative
to energy sustainability, cooling, the
water.
Um
You know, I know that some investors
laugh when they hear this, but obviously
Elon Musk is putting forward long-term
plans.
>> Solar panels
>> centers in space powered by solar.
>> Yep.
>> And
you know, there are some people that
think that that's science fiction.
But if you take a step back and start to
ask some questions,
you know, it becomes a little bit more
clear. We're working on an arc, a full
model relative to dimensioning the
economic feasibility of that. Remember,
SpaceX and xAI
um combined in the last week you know,
at a valuation of 1.25 trillion US
dollars.
Um and they say they're still intending
to go public.
>> Mhm.
>> Some people are saying that that raise
uh is still going to have primary
capital raise numbers as high as 50
billion dollars have been thrown out.
Now, Starlink is a pro- is profitable.
Uh the SpaceX business is cash flow
generative.
Why does a company need 50 billion
dollars?
I I think the logical conclusion is that
the data centers in space is is a is
very real, that this is not um just a
story. It's not science fiction. And
again, at arc we're working to and we we
we would publish along the way as we
have this, what these models look like.
But remember, Starlink has covered the
planet
in satellites. That would be very hard
for another company to copy. That'd be
hard for a government to copy.
>> Yeah.
>> Right? They're uniquely positioned. They
have brought launch costs of uh freight
down uh on a cost curve decline about
90%.
>> Mhm.
>> Um we think that they that um that
freight costs that they can get another
90% decline here as we look out over the
timeline that we're talking about.
They're also it's not a monopoly, but
it's a pretty small set of companies
that can launch uh at at those
economics.
>> once every hour.
>> I I Like I said, there are few to no
companies that can match even launching
at all, let alone launching for
themselves to do it, let alone a launch
company that already has a mesh network
of satellites covering the planet that
can that can send data and broadband
effectively in a latency-free manner
instantaneously.
>> Mhm.
>> So, what sounds to some as fiction and
crazy and pie in the sky,
if you suddenly start to put the pieces
together of what's actually required,
>> Mhm.
>> who has that? What company has that?
What person controls that? And and you
start to get
obviously to Elon and you get to SpaceX
as that company. Data centers are not
going away. Our need for compute
processing, for storage, for tran quick
transfer transmission of data
um
is going to continue to grow at an
exponential rate. We see that obviously,
as we said, these adoption curves are
staggering.
And so, the gating factor to that
happens to be the very thing that SpaceX
is uniquely and I I would dare say
solely
um positioned to to tackle. You don't
have the energy problems in space. You
don't have water problems in space
because you don't have water, but it's
cold there. So, you don't have heating
problem, either. Uh you would have data
transmission problems, except for
Starlink.
>> Mhm.
>> So, I think that
um I think it's going to be very
exciting uh as we look forward. I think
some of the
uh
naysayers
uh and those who are skeptical of AI and
skeptical of the ability to build the
infrastructure at all, let alone in a
sustainable manner,
radically discount something that if you
start to look at the ingredients
necessary, actually are already in
place.
>> If you have to take a guess, how far
away from, you know, that actually
happening?
>> That's a dangerous question. I mean,
>> He says four four to six years
>> He does and and that's the thing is the
reason I say it's a dangerous question
is it's it's dangerous to doubt Elon
Musk.
>> Oh yeah.
>> A lot of people have doubted him a lot
of times over the years and a lot of
people have lost a lot of money doubting
him. So he said four to six and I'm I'm
reticent to just immediately say that
seems too fast. I will say that at Arc
you know sometimes you look at some of
the predictions and you have to adjust
for a timeline because Elon is the type
of manager who set stretch goals and who
pushes his team to achieve things that
others think are impossible or
impossible on that timeline. Is that
four to six a realistic goal or is that
a stretch goal for his team? Let's say
we add a fudge factor in there just to
do it and say that it's not four to six
it's really eight to 10 and I've you
know almost doubled his timeline just
artificially.
>> Yeah.
>> But even if that's true eight to 10
think about the unbelievable
transformation that the world would have
in almost every single way if that
actually is achieved in eight to 10
years. Let alone four to six if he
actually hits his own timeline. So
I think I'm comfortable saying of an
extra fudge factor on Elon but I also
say that with the caveat that it's very
dangerous to doubt him and I think he's
starting with an awful big head start
relative to the satellites and the the
freight rockets that he has the AI
engine that is all now under the same
company and of course don't forget
Tesla. I mean Tesla could be part of the
solution as well. These could you know
in some ways Tesla is the world's
largest AI project from the data that
they have but also from effectively the
supercomputers on four wheels that they
have driving all around the planet that
can supplement
or could bridge the gap. You know we
don't know. That that we don't know but
it's certainly
another advantage that he has that
others don't.
>> Another interesting things he said
recently that if AI and robotics scale
the way he expects
>> Yeah.
>> uh saving for retirement may not even
matter.
>> I I think that has to be put into proper
context.
>> Okay.
>> Right?
I I think Elon is thinking 3D chess.
People sometimes hear that concept in
checkers.
And what I mean by that is really two
things.
I think there's certainly a scenario
where basic needs um are accounted for.
And that uh surplus abundance uh
productivity allows for a world in which
um
you know, that need to at least in
developed worlds first is how this
typically works.
You know, is alleviated.
But
there's always the human nature of
relative positioning. You know, the
other piece of this is he specifically
referenced retirement as part of that.
>> Yeah.
>> But
our chief futurist at Arc, Brett Winton,
likes to point out very quickly
retirement we're using our mindset of in
2026 what retirement means.
But
but let's take a step back. If you have
the technology and you have mobility and
those aren't gating factors and AI can
incorporate uh into everything you do.
And mobility is not a problem either
from EVTOLs, from self autonomous
vehicles, you don't have to do this.
What working means and your ability to
transfer knowledge or to add value to
things from afar
>> Mhm.
>> is a totally different construct than
what we think of as work today.
>> Right.
>> And so
you may want to continue to do those
things well into ages that we no longer
say you do those things now because
technology allows it. And that's even
thinking about AI and the and the way
that we're thinking about it now. You
know, you know, a company like
Neuralink, what what what are the
possibilities? Obviously, we take all
these things to the extreme. Uh the
ability to add value, add productive
value from all people of all physical
conditions and all locations, of all
mental states, is very likely in a
construct that we can't even imagine
today.
And so
I think you have to think of the word
retirement as it might mean, not as we
mean it today, also, when we say that.
>> I love that cuz I've been watching a lot
of YouTube videos talking about this. I
guess people just really want to stop
working.
>> Well, they want to I mean, they want to
they want more Right. And then And
that's the beauty is so much of this is
about unlocking
uh discretionary time.
>> Right.
>> Like even even even take for example,
you know, autonomous driving.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, you you're paying a pretty
high price, truly, when you drive your
own car.
Because that's time you could be doing
something else. Now, you could be doing
something that you're compensated for,
adding productive economic value into
the system. You think about
how much would GDP grow if that
percentage was converted into productive
economic activity. Massively. Your own
time, your own hourly wage
that you're spending driving
>> Mhm.
>> could now be
constructed
adding value. But at the same time
for most people, for the vast vast vast
majority of people, driving is not a
calming soothing recreational relaxing
activity. You also could be watching
Netflix.
>> True.
>> You could be vibe coding and creating
the next
game, the next app, the next invention.
And so those things rapidly also
transform. The technology builds new
industries, new services, new forms of
entertain- The new not working is going
to mean something different than what
not working today. Today, if you clean
your house, you know, that's in theory
an economic loss because you could have
been doing something. If a robot does it
for you, how are you going to spend your
time? Some people may say, "I don't want
to work." And that's fine. Some people
may say, "I don't mind working when I
don't have to do these other things that
I'm really uncompensated labor for. I
don't want to drive or drive my kids. I
don't want to clean my house. I don't
want to do my laundry. If a robot can do
that for you, and you have that time
back, now you have that leisure time.
Now, maybe I don't mind working. I don't
mind stimulating the mind. It's just
that the other my uncompensated work
can be done by robotics and AI such that
I now actually want to do productive or
creative or value-add work. So, again,
I agree with it, but I we have to be
very careful to not use the construct as
the world we're living in today in the
same way that retirement doesn't mean
today what it meant two generations ago,
either, right? That was everybody uh you
know, developed countries had pensions
and the government and their kids were
retired at 65 in a mandatory way, and
they were taken care of single uh income
per household on average. Like,
retirement just meant something
different. You know, there was more
division of labor within uh within the
nuclear family.
That's gone away. So, we can't Today, we
can't use a construct from the '50s and
'60s. We need to make sure that when
we're projecting 20, 30, 40, 50 years in
the future, we're not using today's
construct, either.
>> Big Ideas 2026.
>> Yes.
>> What an awesome report.
>> Thank you. We're very proud of it. Our
research team, all credit really goes to
the research team at ARK. We have an
outstanding research team. Our directors
of research, our analysts, our
associates, our portfolio managers,
really, they they do so they put so much
blood, sweat, and tears into this. It is
the centerpiece
uh really of everything we do on an
annual basis. So, we're extremely proud
of it. Obviously, anybody watching can
download that report free on our
website. They just need to search for
ARK Big Ideas 2026.
>> Is the AI boom taking capital away from
Bitcoin?
>> Well, I think that at the end of the
day, it's there there's a single
pile of global capital. And so on the
margins, institutions and retail have to
make a decision where to allocate that
dollar either from an investment or a
speculation standpoint. I think right
now there's a lot of things that are
probably taking some marginal dollars
away. I I think you look at AI, that is
certainly a case whether you're getting
AI exposure through private equity
venture or through public.
I think you look at prediction markets,
you know, the Kalshi Polymarkets. The on
the margin is that taking away from
crypto? Probably right now.
You look at the last couple of months
we've seen significant speculation in
commodities in the precious metals
space. The charts for silver, gold,
platinum, palladium, copper all look
like meme stocks.
>> Yeah.
>> That capital that speculated on that and
likely used leverage also had to come
from somewhere
that was not speculating on that space
to that degree before that. Was that
capital in crypto and Bitcoin before
that? Quite possibly, almost assuredly
some of it.
Where did the capital come from to be
investing in the leveraged ETF space?
Again, it had to come from somewhere. It
was allocated somewhere else. The space
didn't exist. Now it's obviously, you
know, doing large numbers. Where did it
come from? On the margin could some of
that be from crypto? Probably.
Um and and so
you look at this, it's to some extent
that marginal dollar of global capital
is a zero-sum game. These things are
priced at the margins. And so they do
crypto does not have the luxury of
operating in a bubble.
It is now operating in the global
marginal
dollar
whether institutional or retail and yes
I think these all have an impact. I
think it's it's more complicated than
that. I don't think that's the sole
driver of the price action we've seen
here
obviously of Bitcoin coming into 67
68,000. It's not because AI got all the
money. It's not because prediction
markets took all of the capital. It's a
lot more complicated than that but I
also think it's a little naive to say
that it is not impacting it at all.
>> For people that really want to benefit
from you know the AI wave if they want
to build something let's say
and you know they're not as technical.
>> Yeah.
>> Can't build a phone then you build a
phone case if you can't even build a
phone case try to you know open a shop
and put on you know phone protector.
>> Sure.
>> What is the equivalent of that in AI?
>> I think vibe coding.
>> Okay.
>> Vibe coding is
opening up it's doing two things. It's
opening
creation the coding
um
to a certain segment and audience
that probably never was going to have
the skills to build them at any real
scale or production quality.
And they may have had it as a hobby but
but not more than that.
The ability of vibe coding expands that
market of coders creators dramatically.
You know a company like Replit Replit's
actually in
our venture fund in ARKKVX and and vibe
coding is certainly you know as a whole
that category is very interesting. The
other thing it does though is for
existing coders
they can build applications in almost
entirely new businesses. We were I was
talking to an AI venture studio head who
said he can now do a vibe code sprint
and create an entirely new business with
production grade application platform in
about
three weeks solid coding. Now he's an
experienced coder
with what used to take an entire team 6
to 8 months.
>> Wow.
>> And as that technology and AI gets
better in helping him, that number will
probably come down. Now,
you know, that business model, venture
studio, AI venture studio model uh
certainly is predicated on experienced
coders right now as that labor force to
build those businesses. But, you think
about that, it used to be a team within
an organization of maybe eight to 10
working 6 to 8 months.
You know, now a single person, a skilled
person, but a single person at 3 weeks.
Think about the economics of starting a
business,
uh particularly in areas that maybe
weren't economically viable
at all as a business or economically
viable for a entrepreneur who doesn't
have access to massive amounts of
capital.
When that starts to permeate down the
ecosystem, I think, you know, the most
exciting part of your question is how
much that branches into people who now
can from that business standpoint,
>> Mhm.
>> and how much that expands the potential
of coders who again were maybe not going
to be fully institutional grade Python
experts, but
you know, now can can really generate
real productivity
uh in the space.
That to me is the exciting part of this.
>> You know, AI, crypto, macro, it can be
very overwhelming to a lot of people.
>> Sure.
>> What are, you know, three main trends
that you are paying attention to?
>> Yeah.
Well, one one is a macro trend. I think
it's interesting to pay attention
to the small cap equity space.
>> Interesting.
>> And the reason I say that is, certainly
small caps have been a very challenging
uh place relative to the broad
benchmarks for 8 9 years now, both value
and growth.
And part of the reason I think that is
is that we are seeing companies stay
private longer.
And the proliferation of capital into
the venture and private equity spaces
almost makes
an adverse selection problem
for buying broad-based Russell 2000 type
index of small-cap companies.
Because the very good companies don't
need to go public as small-cap. They'll
stay private longer. They'll have no
problem getting funding. The good ones
will get another round of funding and
another round of funding. And they will
probably go public at some point, but
they'll go public as a large-cap company
or maybe a high mid-cap company. And
obviously in the case of some like
SpaceX, it would be a mega mega cap
company. And so
you know, what does that look like for
small-caps
or buying the index of small-caps? Now,
that does not mean every small-cap
company is a bad company. I want to make
that very clear. We own some small-cap
companies, but it does mean that a rifle
shot approach for why do you own
specific small-cap companies is going to
be necessary. Some of the some of the
biotech, for example, went public and
will probably continue to go public at a
smaller cap
just because they need the public
markets for funding and it gives them
more visibility as targets for M&A if
they if their business model is to be
acquired by a larger pharmaceutical. You
know, that that's a different story than
just broadly saying the Russell 2000.
But I think there's a lot of small-cap
companies that
are small-cap public companies because
they couldn't become middle-to-large
private companies.
Could that change in the future? It it
could.
It would have to change only if we have
regulatory change that makes it being a
public company more attractive.
Or if you just really have a drying up
of the capital in the private equity
market, but there's
there's cycles in that, but it's not but
there's no long-term trendlines to
suggest, particularly in the United
States, that that's going to go away.
And as you democratize the asset class,
it's even less likely. So, that's a
macro trend I'm watching. I think that
that's particularly interesting.
Um
you know, the other piece I think right
now
is you look at the conversation around
de-dollarization.
Now, de-dollarization
I I think it's a little bit of an
overblown story. I don't want to
diminish the volatility in the short
term because that certainly can happen
every single time the US executive
branch talks or tweets or
or posts to Truth Social.
But you know, there have been doomsday
predictions for the US dollar almost
every 10 years.
>> What does that mean
to us?
>> Well, I think So, here's where I think
it's very attractive in terms of
innovation companies.
>> Okay.
>> Innovation companies relative to even
equities in their own country. So, let's
just say Let's take the ARKK portfolio
relative to say the S&P 500.
ARKK companies are not sitting on the
large stockpiles of cash
that large-cap US equities are.
You know, those companies have a lot of
cash. In theory, that cash is being
devalued if the dollar is being
devalued. It's typically They're US
companies, so it's denominated in USD.
And they also have large multinational
books of business. So, the weakening
dollar
will hurt them in terms of some of their
commercial activities. Obviously you
know, if they can sell their products
abroad, it might make it more
attractive. But we're talking about
large-cap multinational that, you know,
has a much more sophisticated business
model than just selling goods to
international.
But
you know, the easiest version is they
have a lot of cash. If the dollar It's
in dollars. If the dollar is worth less
their company is exposed to headwinds.
Our companies are aggressively investing
in the explosive growth potential that
innovation lends it.
And they're not carrying massive cash
balances. So, on a relative basis
>> why?
>> Well, it's I it's it's one of the
reasons why. It's not the only reason
why, but I I think that becomes a
tailwind on a relative basis even within
US equity public equities.
Um obviously, we think the fundamentals
as shown in Big Ideas have massive
top-line revenue growth, technological
adoption,
um you know, significant
fundamental growth rates and
opportunities that are extremely
attractive. But, there's also these
macro forces. So, I would suggest to you
that um you know, they're better
positioned in that world. Of course,
we're sitting in Hong Kong right now.
For Hong Kong, they're pegged to the US
dollar. So, that's you're not you're not
really you're not nearly as exposed to
some of the currency. You know, in other
countries though if they are going to
rotate from US equities their
established book of business is probably
in the S&P 500 and the Nasdaq 100. So,
if you have Japanese, if you have
Chinese, if you have European, if you
have Australian investors
worry about the dollar and want to
rotate out of US equities. And I'm not I
don't mean entirely, I mean on the
margin. What is very likely the actual
transaction? It's probably sell the S&P
500 and QQQ and Nasdaq. Because that's
the biggest component that they have.
That's the large cap dollar heavy
companies, cash balance heavy companies.
Now, they're still going to have to find
growth. Especially if you're in a
declining interest rate environment
which the US certainly seems to be.
You know, Australia raised rates this
week by a quarter point. They say they
might raise them again. We might see a
rate hike in Japan for example, but but
by and large globally still probably
have because the US it's weighted so
heavily to the US. You probably have a
a falling rate environment. And so, you
still need growth. And and you're not
going to go completely out of equities.
So, now you've rotated out of
the Mag 7 is the is the largest
percentage weight in the S&P 500 and the
QQQ.
Though if you're rotating out of US
equities blindly, those companies are at
risk. They're probably fundamentally at
risk because of cash balance, but
they're also at risk just purely on a
rotation from an index standpoint. The
innovation companies aren't because
they're not major components of the
broad-based indices. And they have the
highest growth rates. And they don't
have the headwinds. And then the last
thing from a macro standpoint is
we still believe the US is looking ahead
at rate cuts. Certainly
um Warsh has been nominated to lead the
Fed. It's very likely he got that
nomination with some assurances that
rate cuts were in the future.
We saw even at the last meeting where
rates were held steady that there were
two dissenting votes, and those were
both dissents because they thought we
should have cut by a quarter point, not
they certainly weren't talking about uh
hikes.
And so, if you once that settles in in
terms of new leadership at the Fed,
um I think you're looking at a year. The
market is pretty close to pricing in two
cuts this year.
I think there's
a potential surprise in the market if we
get three or four. And and I'm not
saying I'm fully predicting four, but I
wouldn't be surprised to see more than
two on the concept of this is an
election year. If the polls start to
look like they're moving away from the
Republican Party and and President
Trump, that'll be even more pressure
he'll exert. He just named the person
new to the Fed under what is likely an
implicit agreement relative to the
direction rates should go. I think that
that's a call option tailwind for the
market.
But what companies are most exposed to
benefit from that? You know, people talk
about duration and interest rate
sensitivity, and they typically are
talking about the fixed income portion
of their book. But, equities can be
duration sensitive as well.
And when you're talking about innovation
companies that have explosive long-term
growth rates,
uh and are not necessarily
um being priced based on EBITDA,
then those are your most duration
sensitive equities.
>> Mhm.
>> And so again, I think uh disruptive
innovation disproportionately
looks to benefit from being duration
sensitive in a cut environment where
it's almost assuredly more likely that
we'll surprise to more cuts than
surprise to fewer cuts. So, that's a
that's a call option there.
You they're not as exposed to the dollar
dedollarization.
You're still going to need to have the
highest growth rates in an in an
environment where you are going to need
to look for growth.
And you have very attractive
fundamentals. Maybe AI uh people are
worried about valuations, but there's a
lot of parts of the market that have not
seen that valuation expansion.
Blockchain, crypto certainly being part
of it. Uh biotech has shown signs of
recovery here in the last 3 to 4 months,
but is coming off of 8 years of having
valuation punished. So, there's a coiled
spring there in that space.
Um you know, you have some of the
heavier asset uh including, you know,
your autonomous vehicles, some of your
energy, some of your uh drones that has
not seen the valuation expansion that
we've seen in some of AI.
So, there are a lot of attractive
innovation companies even if you're
worried about about AI. And again, for
the real leaders and beneficiaries,
we're not.
Um we're actually happy the market's
worried. The more worried they are, the
the greater the wall of worry, the the
greater upside a bull market typically
has when it breaks out. Um but, also
just a healthier market in general.
Um you know, I look at all of those
macro things, and I think to myself,
that is a call option for disruptive
innovation in 2026.
And liquidity shouldn't be an issue
In December, the Fed pivoted from
quantitative tightening to quantitative
easing. You know, that liquidity is just
starting to hit the market. Trump
accounts, $1,000 per child, US equity
they're going to go into US equities.
That's just that that hasn't hit yet. Uh
April is tax refund given the tax
scoring that was passed last year.
There's a good chance for outsize refund
for a lot of uh taxpayers in the US. And
I know I'm being very US-centric on
this.
But I think, you know, where we are
looking at innovation, it's still pretty
heavy in the US market. Uh certainly
there are pockets of great innovation
and great innovative companies globally.
But there's a lot of tailwinds that
really support allocation to innovation
and innovation doing well in 2026. And
again, I go back to investors have been
very happy when they've sized in their
portfolio and they've rebalanced in
because the charts look very very
different. They've had they get massive
upside capture at times their core is
actually being disrupted. And it's
they're not overweight and they've
they've shown discipline, you know, in
periods where the market has risk off or
retreats to the broad base.
Uh and I think that that it is that
strategy
and again, that strategy I would also
recommend for crypto
um
is tried and true and I think that 2026
will be another fruitful example of
that.
>> When you say crypto, are we talking
about all crypto or Bitcoin?
>> I I don't think just Bitcoin. I
certainly am not saying all crypto,
either, just to be clear. Uh you know, I
think that uh in the same way it's very
dangerous to paint AI with a broad brush
and say all AI is AI in the way that it
was really dangerous to say dot com and
all dot com uh during that period. And
and I'm not trying to equate AI to dot
com, but I'm just these periods where we
broadly paint brushes.
You know, in the same way, I just spent
the last few minutes not painting all US
equities the same or all small caps the
same. We need a matur- uh a maturation
of crypto to not just say all crypto,
but we also need a maturation to not
just then when we don't say all crypto
to then just only say Bitcoin. Right? We
we need to say that there are
you know, there are
five, six,
you know, leaders that are showing you
know, clear differentiation
fundamentals. Then there's obviously
smaller projects that if people know
well, they will
you know, have the ability to invest in
and they'll and make rifle shot
decisions. Um, but you know, certainly
when you look at Bitcoin, yes, I would
say Bitcoin, Ethereum.
>> In 2026?
>> I think so. I mean there's a lot that's
come out of this market. I don't think,
you know, we've clearly had the
liquidity. We go back to October. We
look at the four-year cycle. I mean,
you're giving me till the end of the
year, so I get the benefit of saying
this over 10, 11 months, but I I think
as we get towards the end of the year,
you know, you're seeing some of the
volatility, some of the chop, a healthy.
Now, this has gone farther than what
people would like and and
and again, there's a lot of reasons for
that, but I think you've also had a
deleveraging and you're going to have
more liquidity in financial instruments
globally. Both of those things tend to
be seeds for
a strong forward-looking outlook.
And I think where we are right now, you
know, it it tested a few times. It had
you know, we bounced around this 65,
66,000 kind of level here, 67,000. Um,
you know, at least as we're doing this
interview, it hasn't you know, it hasn't
broken to the downside of that. It's hit
it, it's bounced, come back into the
70s, hit it, it's come back. You know, I
think it's trying to establish a base
here. If that's what happens, that would
be a positive sign.
>> What I'm hearing is your thesis on
Bitcoin hasn't changed.
>> Long term, no, it hasn't changed. I
think you're seeing the growing pains of
Bitcoin become an instrument of part of
the overall global financial system.
>> Mhm.
>> That means things like derivatives, like
futures, perps, um, like uh, structured
notes.
um, ETFs, ETFs that have options. That
means the overall vol probably
will be lower, systemic, you know, vol.
Obviously, there's a lot more liquidity,
but there's also a lot more leverage,
and there's a lot more sophisticated
instruments that have automatic risk
cells rather than making a fundamental
decision or to to sell or to hoddle.
And so, we just have to recognize that
this is a new phase.
The market it all, you know, it works
differently. There's more things to
consider.
But there's natural growing pains. We
saw that. We've seen this in other asset
classes as they've been integrated into
the traditional financial system. In
fact, there's a lot of examples of it.
And so, I think it's actually healthy.
Um, it's never fun, but, you know, we we
are at that 4-year period as well, and
Bitcoin's seen this a number of times,
and people know that,
um, you know, a steep pullback does not
mean the end of, you know, the end of
the story, and that the long-term
fundamental outlook continues to be very
attractive and very strong.
>> I would love to have you comment on
Ethereum. Um,
people have been disappointed.
>> Sure.
>> Uh, but Ethereum has a lot of utility.
>> Does utility equal price?
>> In the long term, I think yes.
>> Okay.
>> In the short term, there can be
dislocation.
>> Mhm.
>> Education is a huge plays a huge role.
Speculation plays a huge role.
Um, balance sheet access.
Um, opportunity cost.
Right Right now, you might like the
fundamental story, and there is a lot to
like relative to the fundamental
adoption and the value being treasured
from the Ethereum protocol.
But that marginal dollar, that capital
cost of that dollar right now could have
been put to silver, which also has a lot
of utility. It's different kind of
utility, but it's a lot of utility, and
that has made people returns in the
thousands of percent in a matter of
months, and even more than that if you
annualize them. So,
I think there's a reversion to the
value. I mean, in in some spaces you
would call it intrinsic value if you
Some people don't like that word in the
blockchain crypto. So, what we'll say is
we'll use just just value.
But, you know, the adoption and the
utility, those those stories are real.
Those are those are not made up stories.
When you look and and and this is
adoption and utility also by some of the
largest institutions globally, largest
businesses, both financial services and
otherwise.
So,
there's
as that education filters into the
market, as other speculative stories
play out, as
as we also get to a more
crypto beta driven world, not just
Bitcoin is the North Star and only
Bitcoin,
I think that Ethereum stands to benefit
from that. It certainly has been
disappointing to some investors,
but
you know, in a way,
that's that's the story of
innovation as well, investing in
innovation. Sometimes you recognize the
value and see the fundamentals before
the market as a whole, and when the
market realizes it, it tends to be
sharp, sudden and sharp, and suddenly
that's priced in and you can have
violent moves to the upside because it's
not really
destroying volatility or destroying
value. What it is is it's it's it's just
storing it ready for that spring to
uncoil. Remember, AI was that way. We
didn't know about AI and then suddenly
ChatGPT came out and suddenly everybody
suddenly had AI. AI was the only thing
you talked about. Two days earlier,
nobody talked about it. It wasn't in the
news, it wasn't in the media. I mean,
sure, computer science and like if
you're deep in the weeds and you maybe
knew it was coming, but you didn't know
the specifics and then suddenly
magically one day the market said, "Oh
my gosh, ChatGPT." And then Chinese
models came out as well and the market
said, "Oh my gosh, it's it's good and
it's getting cheaper.
This is going to be powerful and now
it's the only thing, you know, the
market wants to talk about. There were
people who were frustrated for years
that you know, Open AI and others were
these large language models were making
massive fundamental gains both in terms
of adoption and their capability, but
nobody was valuing them. Nobody was
talking about them. Nobody was pricing
them into any sort of uh equity like
return. And then suddenly it was
everything.
And so I think
in the long term, the value is by the
market and accrues to
uh to investors. There can always be
short-term dislocations, especially in
misunderstood technologies,
underappreciated, undercovered,
or just when there's a lot of other
opportunity costs for capital in the
market.
>> Let's say an investor has, you know,
100k sitting around. What is, you know,
right now a good idea to allocate that?
>> Yeah, I mean I'll say it more generally
than any specific recommendation, but I
I think discipline around asset
allocation in the modern definition of
asset allocation is is critically
important. They need to understand their
own time horizons and risk tolerance.
You know, my simple recommendation is to
is, you know, is to is to evaluate
yourselves and size those appropriately.
They all play a role.
Um it's dangerous to look at these
things in isolation and not look at them
as part of the whole. That's where I
think people get into trouble. I think
the macro
uh is setting up
it for 2026. I don't, you know, but
whether it starts tomorrow, whether it
starts in a month or a quarter, that I
you know, I'm not really commenting on
that. I think there's a lot of macro
aspects that uh are very positive.
Um it's not that there's not risks.
There's always geopolitical risks and
certainly there is more volatility in
the US equities in particular
and treasuries
given the style of the US executive
branch as it's currently occupied.
Uh it does add risk. Uh, it probably
though adds more volatility than true
long-term risk.
Uh, and that's either something that
investors can try to take advantage of
or they or or or they need to be honest
with themselves whether they can handle.
Um, but there is certainly opportunity
caused by it.
And
uh, when you have a combination of macro
uh, and fundamental uh, positioning
um,
and you and you size that correctly, I
think that
you know, there are there's some very
attractive things right now in the
market and we're of course we're sitting
in a conference that right now,
you know, it's more attractive today
than it was a month ago. So, uh, you
know, we're in the right place to have
that conversation.
>> That was beautifully said. Thank you.
Before I wrap this conversation up,
um, maybe an advice or suggestions to
young listeners,
uh, what type of skills do they need to
obtain to survive in this
uh, ever-changing world?
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, I think a lot of young people
look at their own parents
and they're frustrated
by their parents
inability to operate certain
technologies.
Whether that's with their phone
>> I've been in IT service for my mom
>> Yes.
>> That's right.
>> Yeah, but isn't that just
>> Okay, but let's Okay, but let's like
like let's unpack that, right? Whether
it's something that they don't know how
to do with their phone or they can't
order an Uber or they any could be
anything.
>> Okay.
>> And I know a lot of young people have
frustrations with what they would call
technological
Luddites or or idiots in some cases that
speaking of their own parents who they
love dearly.
And my recommendation would be
let that be a lesson.
Us included.
Let's commit right now to not be those
people, not be our parents in 20, 30,
40, 50 years.
And are we going to take a mental
attitude of
I'm going to be like a young person,
embrace the next thing.
Or are we going to do exactly what our
parents did and complain about how
things were better back then and they
don't know how to use things and they're
not built for them.
You know, I think that's the number one
thing. You can make that more targeted
into specific use cases. You could learn
to code, vibe code.
The barriers have fallen dramatically.
You could learn about blockchain. It's
very likely that that's going to seep
into every part of your life. I mean,
you can pick specific areas and go
deeper. And I think the job market for
young people and looking into the future
is going to be a lot more about um being
very deep in something, knowing
something really, really well, more than
it is about knowing a lot of things a
little.
Because AI can do that for us, right? We
don't AI can do a lot of things a
little. You're going to have to go
deeper
and add more value than what AI is going
to be able to do. And that's absolutely
possible. But you're going to have to
it's a mind shift.
And alongside that, what I would say is
you need to be very good at the things
AI can never replace.
>> Love, empathy.
>> Love, art. I mean, I know that they say
AI can do art, but can it really do art
in the way
I can't perfectly articulate to you
what's different, but it's not the same.
That's that artistic. And AI can make a
a painting.
It's good. AI can write music. It's
good.
AI can write a novel.
It's good.
Are they ever really great?
>> Mhm.
>> Right? And that's the human aspect.
Also, personal interaction. So, it's not
just love, but it's also the personal
the interact the ability to interact
with people. I think there's a danger
young people have gotten so digital that
they forgot that we still live in the
physical world.
>> Yeah.
>> And I would say it's going to be
critical. AI is digital and it's really
smart and cheap and available and
productive. You better be really good in
the physical world cuz it's really good
in in digital world. We we've seen our
parents, let's not copy them. Let's
always be open-minded to the next thing
ourselves. Don't let ourselves fall into
the same trap we we don't like of
others.
Become an expert in something deep. Uh
particularly something with the new
tools that are available.
And also really excel then in the things
that make humans human that AI will
never be. And if you do those things, I
think
the sky is the limit for young people.
>> AI could never do this.
>> I I hope not. I'm It's keeping It's
keeping us in these positions. There are
certain things that are going to be very
hard to replace. The actual human
interaction, even if technology is
theoretically available, theoretically
possible. And it's going to take smart
people on the technology side, smart
people on the financial investment side
to figure out where those lines are,
because that's how
effectively, you know, these returns and
investment and how productive ultimately
the economy and society is.
>> I would definitely urge people to
download Big Idea 2026. Everything we
touched on today um is in that report.
>> Yes.
>> And definitely share this episode with
your friends and family, cuz
what a great conversation.
>> Absolutely. I really enjoyed it. Thank
you.
>> Thank you very much.